# Anirudhan J. Rajagopalan

linkedin.com/in/rajegannathan github.com/rajegannathan

### Summary

Software Engineer with around 5 years of experience in Fullstack Web development. Currently pursuing Masters in Computer Science at New York University with focus on Machine Learning, and Deep Learning. In my next career, I would love to solve interesting challenges using Machine Learning.

# Education

### Master of Science, Computer Science

Dec 2016

Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University.

CGPA 3.75/4.0

Course List: Deep Learning, GPU — Architecture & Programming, Computational Machine Learning, Foundational Machine Learning, Web Search Engine, Realtime & Big data analysis.

## Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology

May 2010

Government College of Technology, Coimbatore

CGPA 8.01/10.0

## **Academic Projects**

2015 - 2016

### Improving classification accuracy on STL-10 dataset.

Torch (Deep Learning)

Used convolutional clustering on around 100K unlabelled images to learn the first layer of features used in the convolutional network. This improved the classification accuracy by 2%.

### Grasp & Lift Detection.

Python, Numpy, Scipy, HPC

Used **VLAD** feature representation and SVMs for the multi class classification problem of detecting a person's hand movements from EEG signals.

## Liver & Pancreatic carcenoma classification.

Python, Numpy, Scipy, HPC

We classified liver and pancreatic cancer using unbalanced DNA protein expression data. We got an accuracy of 97% inspite of having an unbalanced data with more features (500K) than samples (700).

# Correlation analysis of taxi ridership and public events.

Spark, Hive, Python, HPC

Using NYC taxi ride dataset (26GB) and events data from Eventful API, we were able to find a 60% increase in the ridership of NYC taxis when a public event happens in the locality.

## Work Experience

Around 5 years

### **Data Science Intern**

Eyenuk Inc, Los Angeles, CA.

Jun 2016 — Aug 2016

- Explored the classification of Diabetic Retinopathy with Residual Networks against VGG.
- Setup a scalable production AWS deployment using VPC, Route 53, ELB, ACM, and RDS.

#### Software Consultant

Canvera Technologies, India.

Jan 2014 — Sep 2014

- Performance Optimizations Load time: ~10 sec  $\rightarrow$  1 sec. Asset size: ~1.5Mb  $\rightarrow$  ~600Kb.
- $\bullet$  Setup the application architecture & development process. Mentored the development team.

### Founding Member

f1circle.com, India.

May 2013 — Nov 2013

- Built the complete application from scratch. (ROR, Angularjs, Memcached, Redis)
- Built Information extraction engine. It extracts name, place, & price info from user's posts.

#### Freelancer

India.

May 2013 — Jan 2015

- Implemented the common sign-on page, branding workflows and modal framework for Vera.
- Built Urblotter (app.urblotter.com) a betting website for FIFA 2014. (ROR, Angularjs).

## Software Enginneer

Insideview Inc, India

Oct 2011 — May 2013

- Developed in-product notification framework using **Drools framework** & **Lucene indexes**.
- Built the Activitystream security framework using AWS Simpledb and custom eventbus.

### Software Enginneer

United Online Inc, India

Jul 2010 — Sep 2011

• Built a RPC framework for spam filtering. Automated day-to-day tasks using Perl scripts.